# PETER WRATKOWSKI

1872 Sapphire Point Eagan, MN 55122 (952) 484–0197 pwratkowski@gmail.com

### **CAREER SUMMARY:**

Application Systems Analyst with 12 years of extensive experience working with waterfall methodology. Business and technical skillset in software development and processes in the debt collection industry. Certified Scrum Master.

- Coordinate with users and clients to ensure deliverables meet business objectives.
- Plan, create and execute test scenarios to ensure business requirements are fulfilled and project deliverables are defect free.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

### **DCM Services, LLC**

### Minneapolis, MN

Sr Application Systems Analyst

July 2012 - Present

Work with Project Manager to coordinate new client onboarding. Provide support for debt collection software system used by account representatives. Ensure client files were coded properly for transfer and processing.

- Took the initiative to researched various job scheduling software systems and implemented VisualCron that manages over a
  thousand programs which transfer files and generate reports for internal and external clients resulting in hundreds of saved hours.
- Created programs to automate reports from various data sources such as MS SQL, Cache database, Excel and flat files.
- Provided clarification and detailed requirements to EDI team for business procedure documentation updates.
- Ensured account flow and processes are in compliance with debt collection and health insurance laws such as FDCPA and HIPAA.
- Taught myself C# programming to replace an unreliable and separated email system with a new integrated program that processes database records and generates hundreds of daily emails with more efficiency and reliability.

### **DCM Services, LLC**

# Minneapolis, MN

Application Systems Analyst

*May 2006 – July 2012* 

Provide support for FACS debt collection software system. Analyze client onboarding documents and provide feedback to internal team members. Load client files into database and review for errors.

- Coordinate with client auditing team to provide reports to external auditors.
- Analyzed vendor and client requirements and established data exchange and processing interfaces.
- Facilitate migration between test and production database instances and verified testing protocols and use cases were documented before migration.

# **HighJump Software**

# Minneapolis, MN

Support Analyst

January 2004 - May 2006

Provided support for proprietary warehouse management software developed by HighJump Software. Fixed defects in customer applications. Coordinated with project teams to ensure go-live deadlines were met. Helped train customers with software.

- Worked with product development team to analyze and fix a loop in our software program that customers were experiencing. This was causing application timeouts on the warehouse scanners and leaving inventory stuck on forklifts and bin locations.
- Coordinated with internal and external customers during go-live and upgrades to ensure testing scenarios were documented and results logged.
- Logged and maintained a list of defects in Clientele issue tracking system. In the time I was employed I entered and resolved over 2,000 issues with the various software applications used by customers.

### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS:**

## St. Cloud State University

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science St. Cloud State University (December 2002)
- Scrum Master Certification (February 2018)

### LANGUAGES AND SKILLS:

SQL, FACS, Foxpro, C#, Java, Database Design, Certified Scrum Master

### SOFTWARE SYSTEMS:

VisualCron job scheduling software, Request Tracker issue tracking system, Visual Studio, IntelliJ IDE, Microsoft SQL Server